Chapter 1: Prologue

This is a single point of divergence story from the fanfic Harry Potter and the Methods of Rationality (www. hpmor .com, remove spaces). Specifically, the divergence starts mid-chapter 82. At the time of this writing HP:MoR is still in progress, and I only know of the events through the current chapter (now 85), so there may and probably will be more divergences, intentional or not, as time goes on. Certainly I'm not going to follow what's going on in HP:MoR slavishly, and background that has not yet been revealed I'll need to create my own material for. (As will become apparent by the end of this chapter, the present is going to be diverging wildly, enjoy the ride!)

I will, by necessity, need to borrow some text from chapter 82 of MoR to establish the place in the story and provide for continuity. Unfortunately, all the ways in which I might typically designate this text would compromise the flow of the story in some instances. I trust the astute reader will have read chapter 82 MoR anyway and be able to distinguish my text from Less Wrong's. Consider this an explicit acknowledgement that I have borrowed some text, and that all appropriate text should be properly attributed to him. Most of the borrowed text occurs from the start to "The boy took a deep breath, and opened his mouth -".

If you have not read HP:MoR yet, I strongly suggest you do so. It is, however, a daunting task, given its immense size. At the very least, you should read its chapters 78-82 (which is actually a surprisingly good starting point for the middle of the story).

"I acknowledge the debt, but the law does not strictly oblige me to accept it in cancellation," said Lord Malfoy with a grim smile. "The girl is no part of House Potter; the debt I owe House Potter is no debt to her. As for the dishonor -" Lucius Malfoy paused. "As for the grave shame I feel at my ingratitude toward the Potters, who have done so much for me -" Lucius Malfoy bowed his head. "May my ancestors forgive me."

"Well, boy?" called the scarred man sitting at Lord Malfoy's right hand. "Go and destroy Azkaban, then!"

"I'd like to see that," said another voice. "Will you be selling tickets?"

It went without saying that Harry didn't pick this particular moment to give up.

The girl is no part of House Potter -

He had, in fact, seen the obvious way out of the dilemma almost instantly.

It might have taken him longer if he hadn't recently overheard a number of conversations between older Ravenclaw girls, and read a certain number of Quibbler stories.

He was, nonetheless, having trouble accepting it.

This is ridiculous, said a part of Harry which had just dubbed itself the Internal Consistency Checker. Our actions here are completely incoherent. First you feel less emotional reluctance to risk your bloody LIFE and probably DIE for Hermione, than to part with a stupid heap of gold. And now you're balking just at getting married?

SYSTEM ERROR.

You know what? said Internal Consistency Checker. You're stupid.

I didn't say no, thought Harry. I was just saying SYSTEM ERROR.

I vote for destroying Azkaban, said Gryffindor. It needs to be done anyway.

Really, really stupid, said Internal Consistency Checker. Oh, screw this, I'm assuming control of our body.

The boy took a deep breath, and opened his mouth -

"Oh, and Master Potter," Lord Malfoy said, "it is well known to this assembly that there are ways in which the girl could become part of House Potter. However, following the tragic events of 1734, in which a certain Archibald Broomhandle attempted to compel poor Aelwen ferch Olwydd to marry him, by arranging circumstances not so disimilar to these – not that I mean to impugn the honor of House Potter in this matter, you could hardly be responsible at your age," Lucius smiled and continued, "the Wizengamot no longer recognizes any sort of contract as relevant to its proceedings if it was not in force before the start of those proceedings."

...and closed his mouth.

"By all means, if you wish to bring her into your house after these deliberations have finished, feel free to continue."

So, Azkaban? said Gryffindor.

They have dementors not in Azkaban, Ravenclaw unhelpfully pointed out. Not many, but enough to damage a 12 year old girl.

The only way to protect Hermione is to demonstrate our dominance over the Wizengamot, said Slytherin. We need leverage.

What happens if we escalate? asked Ravenclaw. What happens if we choose to lose?

Losing means Hermione dies.

Unacceptable! said Hufflepuff.

We know dragons can be slain, said Gryffindor.

While Harry's inner monologue was ongoing, his feet carried him past a stunned Professor McGonagall, and down the dark stone stairs to where Hermione and the dementor were. His attention was fixed on her, her eyes puffy and cheeks wet with tears. Jeers from Lord Malfoy's side of the Wizengamot slid off him.

You do understand she is never going to accept this, said Slytherin.

He stopped before the metal chair.

Harry was not one to stop finding solutions just because he had some candidates. Because some days would be like today, where all the straightforward solutions would be exhausted without effect. This wasn't even his last idea, he'd passed it over originally because it was dangerous. Danger was scary. And because its effects would be permanent. Terribly permanent. Irreversibly permanent.

"Attempting to send a 12 year old girl to Azkaban is an act of war."

It was not what anyone was expecting him to say. There was silence for a full minute.

"How do you intend to fight a war, boy, with no weapons," said the scarred man next to Lord Malfoy, a bemused smile on his face. "And against all of magical Britain no less."

Harry turned, slowly, to face the Wizengamot. He stood straight, head erect, eyes cold as he surveyed the gathered lords and ladies. He could feel the dementor behind him through the two Patronuses.

"You brought me a weapon," Harry said, the pure high pitch of a young boy's voice imcompatible with the deadly seriousness with which it was said. "In your hubris and your arrogance you imagined yourselves it's master."

Some few eyes glanced at the dementor. Dumbledore was looking very sharply at Harry.

Harry was recalling, quite distinctly, facing down a dozen dementors with nothing but a thought and a command. State of mind was key when dealing with dementors. People – other people that is, never Harry – could hear dementors speak because they imagined dementors had minds and could talk. Expectation drove observation. Set up the right expectation, and people's beliefs would cause the dementor to behave in that way. Reinforce it by projecting his own belief at the dementor in a forceful way and the outcome should be a foregone conclusion.

"In a moment, I'm going to cancel the Patronuses and prevent any more from being cast. Then my dementor is going to kiss everyone who voted to send a 12 year old girl to Azkaban."

There was a sharp gasp from off to his right where Professor McGonagall was sitting. Then the room erupted into laughter. Dumbledore was frowning, his eyes looking down and right as if working through a puzzle.

Of course, they didn't believe him yet. The dementor was still 'safely' behind two Patronuses. It was a shocking claim. - two shocking claims actually. It was also certain that no one believed he could actually cancel the Patronuses. No one except Harry. There's a funny thing with belief. Make one unlikely statement and people will reject it out of hand. Make two unlikely statements, and then demonstrate the truth of one, and people were much more likely to believe both. Because he had comingled them, their truth values would be conflated in the minds of the Wizengamot.

And the problem with the Patronus charm was that it worked by tricking your mind into holding onto the right thoughts. The actual manifestation wasn't necessary – thinking the right thoughts was sufficient to protect you from dementors, but it was hard. Hard to keep the mind focused on the right thoughts. The charm provided several useful features: it provided a concrete and physical action you could take, it gave you a totem that you could point to and say 'that is providing me safety', and it shielded others by putting those thoughts between the dementor and them rather than just in your own head. The last was a useful effect, but the others were only useful insofar as they gave you confidence. One problem was that all that confidence was built on an incorrect understanding of dementors. The real problem was that achieving that confidence when faced with the truth behind dementors required an entirely different kind of happy thought.

So all Harry had to do was speak the truth and the Patronuses would pop. One of his two unlikely claims being demonstrated, the members of the Wizengamot would instantly lend credence to his second claim, and their collective belief would drive the dementor's action.

It was Dumbledore who cut through the laughter and brought the room to silence.

"No Harry! Don't!"

Into that silence a boy's voice spoke: "The dementors are Death, and the Patronus charm works by thinking about happy thoughts instead of Death."

Two seconds later, he snapped his fingers.

The Patronuses behind him popped like soap bubbles.

And Harry, filling his mind with the earth among the stars, thrust that thought at Death and said "Kiss everyone who voted to send Hermione to Azkaban, but spare Lucius Malfoy."

The dementor struck many down before they even had a chance to react. Shock and surprise prevented any quick response. As the reality sunk in, suddenly the assembly sprang into motion. Wizards scrambled to their feet, tripping over seats and stumbling into others. Some few drew their wands, far too late, but no Patronuses appeared. Charles Notte attempted to apparate away, forgetting in his panic that most of the ministry was warded against apparition. A handful managed to extricate themselves from the benches to make a dash down the stairs for the door. They didn't make it. The dementor kissed them all. And when it was finished, an impossibly short time later, the Dementor stood before Harry Potter.

Fifty-five. That was the number of the corpses that surrounded the cowering Lucius Malfoy in the stone hall of the Wizengamot. A woman was being noisily sick among the benches for spectators.

Three aurors and a good number of the remaining dignitaries of the Wizengamot all had their wands pointed at Harry.

"I might observe that the only person capable of casting a Patronus in this room is me, much less controlling the dementor at all. And you will all be thinking much clearer with a Patronus present. I recommend you lower your wands and allow me to do so."

The wands lowered, slowly.

"Expecto Patronum!" Harry said, and a brilliantly glowing person manifested before Harry. There were gasps from around the room. The Dementor hung loosely in the air, seemingly unaware of anyone or anything.

You know, said Gryffindor, I'm not sure I'm ok with what we just did.

Not now.

"Hermione, are you ok," Harry said, turning his head.

"No," her voice weak, "Never. Ok. Again."

She was afraid of him, he could see it in her eyes.

"Release her, please," Harry said to the Auror closest to him. "And she's going to need a wand, so unless you happen to have hers on you, I suppose yours will have to do."

Gawain Robards looked plaintively up to the remaining members of the Wizengamot, where Amelia Bones slowly nodded her head. He then tapped the manacles with a short metal rod and they fell away, and while looking at Harry he offered his wand to Hermione.

"Hermione, there's something we need to do."

The look of horror on her face was painful for him to look at. "Haven't you done enough," she said. She stood up but looked ready to bolt.

"Something Fawkes would want us to do." He held his left hand out to her.

Hermione looked up, over Harry's shoulder, to where Fawkes and Dumbledore were. Her face changed, conflicted, the horror warring with something else. He didn't think he could look where Dumbledore was, he was too close to breaking emotionally already. She took his hand as if he might bite her.

"Only because Fawkes wants it."

"Mr. Potter," said Lucius Malfoy, standing, confusion writ on his face. "Why am I alive?"

He considered Lucius for a moment. Then his face softened.

"Because Draco is my friend, and Draco loves his father," he said softly.

Lucius sat down abruptly, looking like he'd been struck.

And Harry turned his attention to the Dementor, where his wand was still pointed and his Patronus stood idly waiting. And the Earth among the stars filled his mind, the promise of a future without death. He heard Hermione gasp beside him as his patronus became impossibly bright, drowning out the other gasps from the room. When it faded, there wasn't a Dementor anymore.

Harry let his Patronus fade. He turned his attention to the remaining members of the Wizengamot.

Loudly he said, "I seem to recall this council just voted to send Hermione to Azkaban. I've changed my mind, I agree."

And Harry filled his mind with fire and righteous fury. A Phoenix soared among the stars above the earth in his thoughts. Then Fawkes was there beside him, in the Wizengamot chambers, and then he and Hermione and the Phoenix were gone.

For about the tenth time in the last two hours, Amelia Bones's mind failed her. She knew she should be doing something, but she just couldn't process what she'd seen. A muggle might have called it a system error, a blue screen of death, all she knew was her brain just wasn't working.

The boy said what? And then what? And then what? And then half the Wizengamot was dead? And then what? What? What!

Amelia Bones was not used to being this flummoxed. She had thought herself reasonably paranoid. She'd never prepared for this. No one expected a 12 year old boy who could command Dementors. No one expected anyone who could pop patronuses without even touching their wand.

One thing and only one thing was clear, she knew where he was going. Azkaban.

Why in the... Oh. Shit.

The boy who could command Dementors without a wand was gone to Azkaban. She should do something about this.

She found she was sitting, so she stood up. Then she stopped.

What do I do? Any aurors I send will be unable to defend themselves against dementors...

She sat down again.

I have a time turner in my office. I have 6 hours to figure out what to do.

She looked at Dumbledore. Dumbledore had his head in both hands, elbows on the podium, and... was he crying? That wasn't a good sign.

I don't think 6 hours is going to be enough time.

Which was about when the rest of the remaining members of the Wizengamot started to come out of shock. Eyes started to turn towards her. She held up a hand to forestall any questions.

"I have no idea what I am going to do. What I can do. But if anyone has any suggestions, please, I am desperately in need of suggestions."

No one said anything.

Six hours is definitely not going to be enough time.

Chapter 2: Azkaban

This took longer than expected. Other projects got in the way, and there were the inevitable delays normally associated with something you do for fun. But here it is, enjoy.

FWIW, I hope to update at least once a month.

I don't consider any of this 'finished', so if you have corrections or suggestions please feel free to be specific in the comments.

There was a sense of burning and fire and flames, pure and warm, and then, suddenly, she was a person again.

The fear was the first thing to hit her. Familiar, mind-numbing horror smashed into her brain, magnified one-hundred times above any previous experience.

A few seconds later she heard the boy's voice say "Expecto Patronum" and the horror went away. Then she remembered the last 20 minutes.

Fifty people dead on the word of an eleven-year-old boy. For her.

Hermione felt sick. There was an empty feeling near where The Biology of Man assured her the pancreas took up residence. And her brain kept insisting on playing back the murders in the Wizengamot in phantasmagoric slow motion. It was the eyes that haunted her. Terrified one moment, utterly empty the next, and the dream-images hung on each corpse across the space of those moments and let her savor it in detail.

It wasn't just that Harry Potter terrified her. And he did terrify her. But now she was complicit. Responsible.

This inevitably sent her thoughts spiraling to her last morning at Hogwarts, where, knowing she had killed – attempted to kill – Draco Malfoy, she had done nothing in the hopes she wouldn't be caught.

True horror, she realized, was not the artificial fear of dementors. True horror was a consequence of choices made for the worse, and having to live with those choices and their consequences. A patronus, or even just running away, would dispel the horror imposed by a dementor. There was nowhere to run from herself.

She realized Harry was looking at her. Sad. Hurt? Then she realized the hand she had given him before was withdrawn as if she'd been bitten. Was that it? What about what he'd done to her?

Think of something else. Fine silty mud sucked at her shoes as she shifted her feet. She noticed her robe was wet from far more than sweat and tears, and realized it was raining. A driving drizzle, if such a thing was possible. Heavy stone walls were vaguely visible through the rain in each of three directions. Where am I? At least that's what she meant to ask.

Instead she screamed "I'm only twelve!" into the rain. Totally overwhelmed, she collapsed to her knees and started crying.

She didn't know how long she knelt in the ooze crying. Once started, the tears just wouldn't stop. At one point she felt Harry put his hand on her shoulder, but she couldn't even summon the will to shake him off.

Then suddenly there was warmth and comfort, like the best hugs her dad gave her. The warmth landed on her left shoulder and brushed against her cheek, cawing softly. She wiped her eyes before looking up.

"Fawkes?" She had forgotten he was there.

Fawkes lifted his head and screamed loudly towards the sky and the rain. She turned her head to look at Harry, who was looking down at her.

"We're in Azkaban, Hermione. The very center. Where the dementors are kept."

She felt the impulse to run in terror, but the peace from the Phoenix reinforced her resolve. She couldn't feel the dementors at all. Why are we in Azkaban? She noticed Harry's patronus, still standing in silent vigil.

"We need to destroy them. All of them."

It was definitely all too much. She was probably going insane.

"I can't even cast a patronus, how are we going to do that!"

"You can, you just haven't thought about the problem."

She wasn't sure what her facial expression was, but she was certain it was good impression of Professor McGonagall. Skeptical would be far too kind a word.

"Hermione, what are dementors?"

"Fear."

"No."

What?

Was this a riddle? Hermione was pretty good at riddles, but this was a riddle that apparently most of the wizarding world got wrong.

Wait, hadn't Harry said something before the world went totally insane and people died?

Hermione hadn't really been paying that much attention to what Harry was saying in the Wizengamot. There'd been the horror of the dementor behind her, and the horror of her impending sentence to Azkaban before her. To say she hadn't been thinking clearly was an understatement of gross proportion. But she had an excellent memory.

Dementors are death.

She wasn't sure that made sense. Yes, death was fearsome. Many people were afraid of dying. She was afraid of dying. But she was afraid of lots of things, including a certain 11-year-old boy, and she was pretty sure he wasn't death. Well, reasonably sure.

On the other hand, Harry was meticulous about "testing hypotheses", to the point where he disregarded the accumulated wisdom of older wizards. She still remembered the bats. He would have collected evidence. Hadn't he been asking other students what they saw when they looked at the dementor back in January...?

"Harry, why were you asking the others what they saw when they looked at the dementor? In January, I mean, when we were learning the Patronus charm?"

"That's not quite the right question."

"You are very frustrating."

So, what was the right question... Well, he also saw the dementor. Maybe he wanted to see if the others saw something like what he saw?

"Did you see the same thing they did?"

"No."

What?

"What did you see?"

"Initially? Nothing."

!?

"Nothing?"

"Dementors' appearances, like their actions, conform to the expectations of people around them. Because most people believe false things about dementors, they see only falsehood. My brain caught itself trying to clothe the dementor in a lie and wouldn't let it, so I couldn't actually see it. To see a dementor for what it really is, you have to discover the truth."

And then Hermione was thinking about Godric Gryffindor's biography, which she had read cover to cover and cried afterwards. Dementors are wounds in the world. Not dead people or other nightmarish concoctions. Wounds. Nothingness. He had known, as Harry knew.

"I suppose we need to go find a dementor then." Hermione couldn't believe she had just said that.

"That shouldn't be hard." Harry deadpanned.

Godric had enough courage to see the truth. Hermione could live up to his example. She had enough courage to have gone in front of a dementor knowing her patronus wouldn't work. She could be a hero, a real hero, despite her fear and her doubt. And her guilt.

It didn't take them long to find a dementor.

The dementor was just hanging in the air limply, totally unaware of anything. No sense of fear attacked Hermione's senses as they approached it.

"Are they supposed to do that?"

"My patronus is kind of overwhelming for them."

They stood there for a few moments in the muck, looking up at it.

"Um, Hermione, I can't really dispel my patronus safely. There's over 100 dementors down here and I'd need to be sure you could call one up immediately if I was even going to attempt that."

"The fear is just a distraction anyway, right? It helps sustain the delusion?"

Harry nodded.

Hermione stared at the dementor hanging in space. She thought of how fearsome the dementor had been in January. She couldn't even look at it then. How it had spoken to her. Except it had told her exactly what she wanted and expected yet feared to hear. She had been worried for Harry, and distrustful of the Professor Quirrel, and she had heard it tell her that the defense professor wanted it to eat Harry. Her thoughts, her fears, projected on the dementor and speaking through the dementor's mouth. It was hard overcoming the power of memory even with it motionless and unaware.

Godric Gryffindor hadn't looked away when he had seen the truth, she was sure of it.

I can be a hero. I am a hero. You frighten me but I am stronger than my fear.

But in that moment her guilt nearly overcame her. How could she be a hero now? Her complicity in Draco's attempted murder, her complicity in the murders in the Wizengamot – these were not the actions of a hero! That was when she realized that dementors didn't really frighten her anymore. Dementors were nothing next to her own guilt.

Where at first the dementor had held an appearance of a terrible death, bloated, organs dangling from large tears in the flesh, it was now merely emaciated and sickly looking.

You no longer frighten me. Hermione stepped closer. Your form is a lie.

She was standing just before it now. Fawkes radiated heat from her shoulder.

No more lies.

In the space of a blink it was gone. Before her there was a nothingness of substance where her mind refused to let her see.

I name you. You are death.

And there, in the mud and rain in the middle of Azkaban, Hermione saw death and comprehended it.

"Show me how to destroy them," she said without turning. Maybe she couldn't be a hero anymore, but her fear of dementors was broken.

Auror Li still wasn't sure what was going on. It wasn't that the recent communication from Director Bones was unusual – it was far beyond unusual – it was her mood. She was shaken. This wasn't the all-business director who, while outraged and alarmed, hadn't just given up when Bellatrix Black escaped. She took charge and had done everything in her power to re-apprehend the fugitive. That she had thus far failed to recapture her hadn't slowed her down. But this...

He looked down at the orders he had requested in writing. If you see anything unusual happening, report it immediately. Do not investigate.

And Director Bones had seemed... beaten. Li couldn't remember her ever being beaten. He had a terrible sense of foreboding. Something awful had happened, not that anyone was telling him anything, and it wasn't something as simple as "Bellatrix Black has escaped from Azkaban" or even "Voldemort has returned". What could possibly be so much worse than that? What could have happened to break Director Bones?

Li looked out the window facing inward to the pit where the dementors stayed from across the room. Something that Director Bones thought was going to manifest here in Azkaban. Expected it to. There was no reason for these orders otherwise.

Auror Li shuddered.

Hermione was certain that this wasn't how things were supposed to work.

"Your happy thought is what?"

"My rejection of death as part of the natural order."

"You just killed 50 people, not one hour ago!"

"Have we not moved past that yet?"

"It was less than an hour ago!"

Hermione stormed off a couple paces. She wasn't feeling much like herself. Her guilt was gnawing at her, and it was making her moody and surly. It threatened to overwhelm her and reduce her to tears again. She needed a warm fire and a cup of tea and chocolate. Lots of chocolate. And a good book. And a day, a week, a month with no Harry Potter. His presence kept reminding her of those awful moments.

"I can't do this Harry. I'm not good enough. I can't be a hero."

"You're the most good person I know," Harry said softly.

Tears gathered at the corner of her eyes. When would she be able to stop crying? She turned halfway. "I feel so guilty."

"You haven't done anything. You were False Memory Charmed into thinking you had killed Draco."

"I did. I woke up and knew, or thought I knew, what had happened and said nothing. And then there's all those people dead..."

"Which is entirely my fault. You were helpless at the time."

"I asked. And I should have known what you might have done. Professor Quirrel was right, you are dangerous."

…

"I can't believe I said that..." she finished quietly.

"That you should have known?"

"That Professor Quirrel was right."

...

"Hermione," Harry began, pausing to find words. "I think its your guilt that makes you such a good person. You can't move past these things because you know they were wrong. And the very fact that you were even connected to something wrong upsets you horribly. Villains don't feel guilty about doing the wrong thing."

When she didn't say anything he continued.

"Maybe its guilt that makes heroes, real heroes, attempt to do the right things. Because they understand the consequences better than most, or feel them more keenly."

It was remarkable what words could do. Not that it made everything better, although she supposed that was part of the point, it was never going to be completely better. She needed to remember how awful it was. But those words gave her hope and perspective. Maybe it wasn't goodness that was lost, just innocence. The gnawing emptiness lessened a little bit. Just a little, but it was enough.

And hero or no, she couldn't let feeling guilty stop her from doing the right thing now. Dementors were evil, and destroying them was the right thing.

"Ok Harry, I'm together enough. For this. For now. Tell me about your happy thought."

And so Harry described the stars in space, perfect and coldly beautiful. He described the completion of the image, the earth as seen from space, among the stars. And you could feel the emotion in Harry's words as he described it – this was something he truly cared about. It was a wonderful image.

But her intuition was that Harry wasn't right. Couldn't possibly be right. Not completely. And yet there was Harry's Patronus, bright and pure in the drizzle.

This is just another riddle. I'm smart enough to solve this.

Dementors weren't physically Death. Sure, they could kill you, but so could a lorry if it hit you. And if you weren't being strictly literal, people weren't the only things who died. Dreams died. Hopes failed. Innocence was lost. Magic faded. People died a little inside every time these things happened. Small deaths before the final one.

She remembered reading The Lord of the Rings and being upset at the end because all the magic was going away. It was ineffably sad, as if all bright colors were become muted and pale.

She had watched in horror as the Wizengamot debated her fate, and those who might have championed her remained silent.

She remembered her shame as Snape castigated her and S.P.H.E.W. She remembered Dumbledore saying nothing. Professor McGonagall hadn't even shown up.

People let evil happen by failing to take action to stop it.

She needed to believe in a future of dreams fulfilled, evil vanquished, and hopes undimmed. She needed a world without all those deaths of spirit. But describing this world in swaths of pretty words wasn't enough. She needed a crystal clear vision, primal, her own metaphor for victory over death. The way Harry's earth among the stars metaphorically embodied his vision of a future without physical death.

A world where Snape praised her? No. That would be a world with bullies still.

And then she remembered Draco helping her up off the floor. Draco who caught her when she slipped on the roof. Draco who visibly distanced himself from all the antagonism directed at her. Draco who she couldn't believe wasn't plotting against her, because he was Draco Malfoy. Draco, who had been doing what was right against all expectation and incentive. It was a strange bittersweet happy thought she arrived at: a world where she could innocently believe in a Draco Malfoy who was helping her.

Her wand came up.

As she set her stance she realized that her world of hope and innocence, her happy thought against the darkness, was beyond her. That even if she made it a reality, there would be no place in it for her. But would Harry's world really have a place for him? We pursue these things so that others may have them because we did not.

"Hermione... you're crying?..."

She ignored him.

"Expecto Patronum!"

A second glowing person joined the first in the pit of Azkaban.

Chapter 4: Truth, Consequence, and Creative Fiction

Announcements!

To the best of my predictive powers to ascertain, this arc will be concluding with the next installment. Unless of course certain characters simply fail to shut up and keep talking for way too long.

Following the conclusion of this arc, there will be an editing pass over all the chapters. Copyediting and whatnot. Probably also looking at some continuity issues (I think I spotted at least one error that I should probably fix).

I know what the next arc is. There will be less Harry, finally. Yes, I'm terribly sorry, and mildly annoyed, that he has featured so prominently. Hermione is the title character for a reason, its time to start focusing on her more.

And last, but certainly not least, I'm looking for betas for some original fiction. Possibly several pieces of original fiction. The first is definitely a sci-fi mystery/thriller short story. If anyone is interested in betaing that or a longer fantasy piece that's in the works, PM me.

Dementor Disaster

Wizengamot Decimated

That was what the headline of the Daily Prophet proclaimed. The exact nature of the disaster was carefully unspecified. Causes were 'under investigation'. And assurances were most definitely made that the dementor in question was 'under control' thanks to the 'valiant efforts of aurors at the scene.'

Due to the volume of prominent obituaries, "Boy-Who-Lived Arrested for Underage Magic" was pushed back to page four. Like the front page, the story was littered with generalities and vague claims. The only statement that committed to anything stated simply 'Mr. Potter is being detained at the Ministry.'

Quietly slipping onto the back page was the innocuous article "Wizengamot Considers Prison Without Dementors". It attributed the supposed motion to the aforementioned disaster on page one. No mention was made of the fact that magical Britain had perhaps three dementors left anywhere on the islands.

Harry Potter folded the paper before setting it aside. The carefully-worded lies and weasel non-statements weren't much of a surprise. Between Lucius Malfoy's control of the paper, what was likely several False Memory Charms used on the reporters present, and crafted statements by Amelia Bones temporarily acting as the head of the government, the truth had been meticulously plastered over. It was hard not to respect the skillful cover-up. Harry wondered if most of the Wizengamot still remembered what happened.

He placed the Daily Prophet on the desk before reaching for the Quiddler, which had been under it. He almost dropped it in shock when he finally got a look at its front page. "Harry Potter Fires Opening Salvo Against Death-Eaters" proclaimed the headline. His mouth worked soundlessly. Apparently several Death-Eaters had attacked Miss Granger, but they had been thwarted by Harry Potter, and most of them were killed in the attempt. Then the Boy-who-lived and Miss Granger had vanished mysteriously to safety.

Harry burst out laughing.

He was sitting in a nicely appointed apartment, somewhere proximal to the ministry building. Presumably this was some sort of diplomatic suite, usually used to house visiting magical dignitaries. The unit, and three others like it, were accessible only by floo network. Despite the impossibility of him going anywhere, there was an auror in the hallway that connected the four units who had been ordered to make sure Harry didn't leave the room. He presumed Hermione was also on the floor, but, having decided that further provoking Director Bones was a poor idea, he hadn't been able to look in on her. But the auror had gladly provided this morning's entertainment, courtesy of the newspapers.

It couldn't be long before someone came to get him. They needed a resolution to this as much as he did.

When Hermione awoke, Dumbledore was standing over her, concern on his face.

"Miss Granger, it is good to see you awake."

She found herself in a strange bed. The room was mostly dark, illuminated only by something which also radiated heat and comfort, oddly placed above and behind her on the back of the bed. She rolled her head back, arching her spine slightly to afford a clear view, and was surprised to see Fawkes perched above her. Hermione pushed herself up to a sitting position.

"Headmaster, where...?"

"Somewhere safe, for the moment at least. Would that I could spare you this, but I must know. Tell me, what do you remember?"

Hermione couldn't bring herself to think of the events of the Wizengamot chamber, not with the peace radiating from Fawkes. But Azkaban was almost a happy memory. She brightened at the thought of the powerful light that had emanated from her. "...I cast a patronus. Harry helped me. It was so bright and pure, and... I could feel it... the peace... as it spread over the people... the prisoners..." She looked guardedly at Dumbledore.

"Is there anything else you..."

"Did you know?" She interrupted

Dumbledore arched his eyebrows in question.

"Did you know about the condition of the prisoners. Of how horrible it was."

There was pain in Dumbledore's eyes, but he was slow to speak. Hermione recoiled against the back of the bed.

"You knew."

"I knew."

"How could you?! How could you let that place exist?!"

The phoenix light brightened from a subdued flame to a blaze. In the harsh light, Hermione could see Dumbledore's shoulders sag a little. His eyes sombre. Overall he seemed diminished. Haggard. Hermione felt a pang of sympathy for him.

"I have no certain answers for you. For all its unspeakable horror, it was a symbol of justice and law to witches and wizards in these isles."

Hermione was looking past Dumbledore, was thinking about the woman that Harry described to her. "It was evil," she said flatly.

"I see that you, too, have learned to speak with what voice phoenices might speak, were they to talk. Maybe it was evil, I can no longer say. But I could not lightly wield power against all opposition, and then, its been a long time since I was a hero."

Hermione said nothing. Listening. Trying to understand the ancient wizard who before yesterday she would have proclaimed a beacon of goodness without question.

"I've been playing this game for too long, waiting for the next hero, for the cycle to repeat, for the story to go on. I thought it was my role, my duty as the mysterious old wizard, holding the fort until a champion was needed when darkness rose once more. But now I find that the hero doesn't need me as a mentor, and the one whom I thought would be champion keeps other counsel."

"Harry..."

"Harry has made his own choices, as he always has."

"Headmaster, how do I save Harry from himself?" Fawkes was now a dim glow, casting long shadows across the wizened face that looked down on her.

"I wish I had the answers for you, Miss Granger. But I am out of answers."

"How can Harry be a hero after... that..."

"Harry is not the hero I referred to."

There was a long moment as they looked at one another, the young witch and the old wizard. Her blood beat audibly in the silence, counting the seconds as they extended into minutes. Dumbledore gave her a sad smile that didn't reach his eyes.

Hermione couldn't stand that smile. It looked like defeat. She broke the silence first, grasping at the first thing she could think of. "Headmaster, will you be taking Fawkes with you?"

"A Phoenix is not ordered. It goes where its heart tells it to go. And like the Phoenix, the cause of the good and the light does not suffer permanent death, but is gloriously reborn. Reborn in the hearts of new champions who will carry on where others left off. The phoenix follows the light."

Hermione glanced at Fawkes again, who was looking down at her, head cocked. "I couldn't."

"He has chosen you, Miss Granger. Would you deny Fawkes his choice?"

She reached up to Fawkes, who nuzzled her hand briefly before stepping gently onto her wrist. She brought her arm down before her, across her body, feeling the warmth of the phoenix clearly. She didn't know what to say to Headmaster Dumbledore.

"Headmaster, I don't understand."

"Don't trouble yourself, young Ravenclaw, it is not your burden to bear. There will be plenty of others for you. And mysterious wizards would fail to be mysterious if we were so easy to understand."

Another awkward silence descended briefly. Hermione broke it quickly.

"And what happens to me now?"

"Mister Potter has secured your freedom. When you are fully recovered, you may return to Hogwarts. Professor McGonagall will be by later today."

"And what will happen to Harry?"

"I am uncertain. He is to be meeting with Director Bones and some others at this moment to discuss the situation."

She felt a succession of contradictory emotions about Harry. It made her stomach ache hollowly and brought tears to her eyes where they glistened, unshed, in the phoenix light.

"I don't want to see him."

"Then you won't have to."

She half-smiled. "Thank you for being here Headmaster."

Dumbledore stood straighter and nodded his head. Sensing the conversation had run its course, he slowly strode to the door from the room. He turned back to her, nearly lost in the shadows of the subdued light, his hand on the door.

"Farewell Miss Granger. May we meet again under happier circumstances." Then he was out the door, closing it softly behind him.

He was gone by the time she'd understood those two sentences.

Harry found himself within a rather plain room, boxy and mostly bare. Grey paint was in various states of peeling about the walls. A rectangular table and four chairs were the room's only ornament. The auror escorting him led him to one of those chairs, facing the other three across the table. Harry pushed the chair back on its rear legs slightly before spinning it about and then sitting on it backwards, straddling the seat and resting his chest against the back of the chair. He looked at the auror, but there was no reaction. The auror left him there in the room.

If their positions had been reversed, Harry would let captive Harry sit. Make him sweat. Of course, Harry had seen muggle crime dramas. The whole thing seemed trite and ridiculous now that he was actually sitting there. Its not like he was going to come to some deep realization about how much trouble he was in, he already knew that. He'd had plenty of time to think while waiting in Azkaban, and again this morning.

Harry was here because he wanted to be here. That gave him power. That gave him control.

To exploit that control he was going to need his dark side. He needed the clarity and he needed the threat of it just below the surface. So instead of thinking about guilt and consequences, he thought about pain. About the woman in Azkaban. About Hermione in the metal chair before the Wizengamot. He didn't fall into it though, but merely readied it, held like a pitbull on a tight leash with a trespasser before it. He was ready.

At last the door opened and three people filed solemnly into the room. Director Bones was first, stepping briskly to the center chair, crisp and professional. Lucius Malfoy followed behind her, taking the left chair. No surprises yet. The third was Professor McGonagall, moving with determination but without her usual energy. Harry forced himself not to frown. He'd been expecting Dumbledore. All of their faces were schooled masks of indifference.

Harry permitted himself a sly smile as McGonagall was seating herself. He was never going to get a better chance to say this. Before Director Bones could assume control by speaking first, he spoke confidently, "I suppose you're wondering why I called you here."

Three sets of eyes stared at him impassively across the table. But there was no backing down now. He was in control here. They were here because he had made them be here, and he wasn't going to concede anything he wasn't prepared to concede. This was his meeting.

"Ahem. Mister Potter..." Amelia finally began.

"That's Potter-Evans-Verres."

"Mister Potter, you do understand the severity and significance of your actions which cause this to be necessary?"

"Have you seen the morning paper? I especially liked the Quibbler headline." He relaxed with his arms crossed before him over the back of his chair.

Lucius's eyes darkened slightly, but he was otherwise the picture of stern composure. Amelia was giving him that look his father gave him when he was angry and wasn't going to let Harry change the subject. The only real reaction he got was from Minerva.

"Harry!"

He ignored her. "You're not looking for proof of my understanding. I would hazard at most one of you cares at all what's going on in my head. What you're looking for is reassurance for yourselves that whatever devil's bargain you make today is the right one. You're looking for guilt so that you can use it to control me. I will not utter meaningless reassurances and I will not be blackmailed by my guilt. Should you find any reassurance after our discussion, it will be because you have reasonably come to the conclusion that the outcome will be better than if we had not talked."

"Mister Potter, these..." Amelia began.

"Potter-Evans-Verres."

"Mister Potter-Evans-Verres," she sighed, "these are serious offenses against state and society."

"Offenses that you seem unwilling to make public. Although the news did make for entertaining reading this morning. Where is Dumbledore anyway?"

"The administration of Hogwarts is represented here, Mister Potter," McGonagall said sternly. Harry filed that under things to think about later.

"Before we talk about anything of substance then... has everyone been read in?"

Harry didn't expect an answer. Instead he paid careful attention to their reactions. Lord Malfoy raised one eyebrow slightly, nonchalantly. Director Bones pupils dilated just a little, her face assuming the poise of someone who knew they were composing their face to show no response. McGonagall's eyes glanced to her right quickly, her mouth open just a fraction, before she regained her composure. Her hands smoothed her skirt beneath the table in distraction.

"Well, I suppose that answers that. Thank you for your honesty."

"As fascinating as this is, Mister Potter-Evans-Verres," Lord Malfoy began, Harry's full last name sharp and precise, "would you please stop wasting our time."

Harry nodded.

"Mister Potter-Evans-Verres," interjected Director Bones. "I am not in the habit of making deals with cold-blooded mass murderers. Before we go any further you will tell me what in the Fiddly-Snocks you were thinking."

"Oh this should be a fun game. Let me guess, I try to find the explanation that I think you will find most sensible, and you try to tell how badly I'm lying?"

"What I want, Mister Potter-Evans-Verres, is the truth."

"That's a great set up, but my Robert DeNiro isn't very good. Maybe after puberty."

Silence.

"Very well. I could tell you that I chose the course of action that I did because I expected it to be better than the alternatives. That I was cognizant of the fact that many of the dead were either Death Eaters themselves or willing pawns of Death Eaters. That I couldn't necessarily name all the names but I'm certain you have your suspicions Director Bones. And that my action, while alarming on its own, will likely prove beneficial in the next war. That would be a lie, although there is certainly truth to it, but it was not what I was thinking. It would be a post hoc justification, and I try to be more honest with myself than that."

"But we shouldn't discard that observation either. Because even if I wasn't thinking that, my actions still have the same impacts, the same consequences."

"And what of the consequences, Mr. Potter, to Miss Greengrass," Professor McGonagall interjected. "She lost her mother yesterday. A mother who, to the best of my knowledge, was never a Death Eater, and never in their thrall. Or there's Theodore Nott, who lost his great-grandfather and guardian, a man who may have been sympathetic to the Death Eaters himself, but that is not salve for a child's grief. They're not the only children who lost family members, although they're the only ones you may have known well. Would you have liked to have taken my place last night when I told each of them. Seen those consequences first hand."

Harry closed his eyes briefly. Somewhere inside a part of him was screaming. He opened them again and met Minerva's gaze.

"And that, professor, is why I'm here, and why we're having this conversation."

He thought he saw relief, if only for a moment, in McGonagall's eyes. No Minerva, you haven't lost me to darkness, not yet. But then it was gone or perhaps he'd just imagined it. He turned his attention back to Director Bones.

"What I was thinking was that any group which would condemn a twelve-year-old girl to Azkaban had such a fundamental values dissonance with me that conflict was inevitable. In effect they, and by extension of the power they wielded as the voting majority of the Wizengamot, the government of Magical Britain itself, had declared war on my values. I said as much to them. To you. I'm sure it did not help matters that the twelve-year-old girl in question was my friend, but I'd like to think that I'd object to anyone my age being sent to torture and murder masquerading as justice. I tried to forestall the conflict with a less drastic solution. I was blocked at every turn. There are some values which I will not sacrifice, not when it is within my power to protect them."

"And you still believe what you did was right," Amelia Bones said. It was not a question.

"It was. They were guilty the moment they voted."

"Self-serving nonsense." Lucius Malfoy pushed himself up from the table. "To hold a twelve-year-old girl's life above the lives of over fifty men and women? Preposterous."

"Should you happen to come across several armed thugs robbing a single man, their weapons drawn, do you protect the man or his assailants?"

"I'm not susceptible to your sophistry Mister Potter."

"You protect the man, Lord Malfoy, because its not just about the one man in his person, its about all the other possible men and women who could and will be in that place if the thugs are not dealt with."

He had raised his head and held Lucius's eyes while he spoke. And then he could feel it, the tiny feelers of legilimency scraping across the surface of his mind. Harry was going to let him find nothing, frustrate him with the fact of his occlumency, but then a wild idea took him. He brought two thoughts to the forefront of his mind, in front of his barriers. The first, something he had read in one of the recent histories. All the power of the dark lord in his scar. The second, a memory. The memory of his voice as he acted as the dark lord, just the voice, a chill whisper in the endless night of Azkaban. Hello, my dear Bella. Did you miss me?

In Harry's mind, but only in his mind, behind his occlumency barrier, there was a sound of fingers snapping.

Lucius stumbled back into his chair, toppling it and almost falling over himself. There was a brief look of pure fear in his eyes before he composed himself again. With deliberate slowness he bent down and righted his chair before reseating himself. Both McGonagall and Bones looked at him curiously before turning back to Harry.

"That seems to have established the facts of the matter," Director Bones said. "Now, as to Azkaban, what exactly did you do with the Dementors, Mister Potter."

"I believe I told you already. I ate them."

"Be more specific, Mister Potter."

"-Evans-Verres. And they are no more. Dust and less than dust."

"No one destroys their strongest weapon voluntarily," Lord Malfoy said, more to the two adults than the child they faced. Harry smiled.

"You conclude he is lying, Lucius?" Amelia said to him.

"That is one possibility," Harry offered, resting his chin on his arms. "There is another."

Lucius had not taken his eyes off Harry. Amelia and Minerva exchanged a worried look.

"Ahem. As to the terms of your incarceration..."

"I believe the only charge you're willing to make public is underage magic use, Director Bones."

"I could have your wand snapped for that alone, Mister Potter-Evans-Verres," the Director of the DMLE said sharply.

"Not that we would imagine doing such a thing to you, Mister Potter, of course," Lord Malfoy said.

This was going to take awhile.

In the end, it wasn't as bad as Harry had been willing to accept. Ten years of imprisonment, here, in the elegant apartment they had been keeping him in already. Access to tutors and educational materials – McGonagall had agreed immediately with him on that. Use of wand while supervised. Visitors permitted. It wasn't much different than his expected future at Hogwarts, albeit a bit longer and without peers readily available. Lucius had become an unexpected ally, and so Harry had merely had to steer the conversation in the appropriate directions and let it run its course.

The exact nature of the agreement would be a state secret, known only to the Wizengamot, who would ratify it tomorrow. It felt, to Harry, that he was being treated like a political prisoner more than anything else. Which made sense, in a way. There had even been a formal declaration of war. This was the peace treaty.

McGonagall had escorted him through the floo travel and back to the apartment, before going to check on Hermione. Harry had wanted to look in on her, but Minerva had been resolute that he should go to his rooms.

There was something slightly amiss when he entered, some nameless difference that he felt more than observed. Intuition making leaps with evidence his conscious mind hadn't fully processed. He walked over to the bedroom and opened the door.

Dumbledore was sitting in an upholstered chair, his purple robes blending into the darkness of the unlit room. His hat was in his lap.

"Good evening Harry. I thought we might speak one last time."

Chapter 6: Bechdel Fail

A/N: What was in the teaser has changed a little bit, but should still be mostly recognizeable. And there's more!

Next month: more Tracey-driven shenanigans. I *think* this arc will only take three months, but we'll see.

In the longer term, I'd like to have some idea what EY's Quirrel plan was before everything went pear-shaped in this fic. However, given how close to the chest he seems to be keeping that, and the long periods of time between updates, I may not have that luxury. We'll see what happens - it may be that I'll just have to assume my crazy theories about where he's going are true. (That might just be more fun anyway, but I would like to keep this to a single point of divergence if at all possible).

Hermione Granger stood before the door to the first year Slytherin common room. She was too scared to knock on the door.

There was a voice in her head saying This is Hermione Granger standing before the Slytherin common room. She is too scared to knock on the door.

There was another voice in her head saying There is a voice in her head saying "This is Hermione Granger standing before the Slythering common room. She is too scared to knock on the door."

There was yet another voice in her head that sounded remarkably like Harry saying something about depth of recursion.

There was still another voice in her head trying out dirty names to call Harry for having introduced her to the concept. A good girl shouldn't have to listen to so many inane voices in her head. She supposed she should be thankful that the worst names she came up with sounded far too comical and cartoonish to actually be considered dirty; she was sure she'd heard something truly foul before, somewhere, but apparently her brain couldn't even think it.

A fifth voice, the only one she felt comfortable assigning to herself in her internal pentalogue, wondered idly if this was what it was like in Harry's head all the time. Or did Harry's brain manage to sound like multiple complicated books in surround sound? She would have to ask him if they were ever on speaking terms again.

She still hadn't even worked her brain up to the task of convincing herself to actually knock on the door, like she'd set out from Ravenclaw to do, when the door opened in front of her. Conversation spilled out around Tracey Davis, whose purposeful expression was replaced by shock.

"Hermione? What are you doing here?" The sounds of conversation from the room stopped. Tracey's eyes went wide. "What are you doing here?"

"I was... um... I wanted to... eheheheh."

Tracey closed the door hard behind her. "Do you know what they'll do if they caught you here?" she indicated behind her with her head. "You need to not be here. Now."

"S-secret stairs."

Hermione didn't move, her mind still catching up with just how stupid her plan was, in retrospect. No, not just in retrospect. She should have thought this through more. Tracey spun around, wand in hand, and bit off "Colloportus" at the door before grabbing Hermione by the arm.

"Move. Now."

Hermione stumbled after Tracey as the Slytherin girl pulled her towards the stairs. The sound of the door rattling behind her finally got her brain to engage her feet. The girls fled.

At the top of the stairs, panting with exhaustion, the girls stumbled to a halt.

"Wha..hea...teyeh...dih...hea...yewe...hing...kyeh...hue...ouer...hoo...heng...?"

"I...I...hsss...hssta...hop." Hermione held up her left hand as she caught her breath.

Their breathing slowly returned to normal. Hermione relaxed her right hand where it rested on her wand; any pursuit had apparently been short-lived, in worse shape than they were, or male and unable to follow. Hermione regarded Tracey. They hadn't been especially close, but Tracey had been in SPHEW. She might have expected aid from Daphne, but Tracey... maybe she'd made a bigger impression than she'd thought. Or maybe Tracey had her own motivations that would sweep Hermione up in some crazy plot that wouldn't even make sense with a flowchart, three colors of highlighter, and a centaur seer. Was that the sound of ominous music playing...

"Was there some clever plan that involved getting beat up by Slytherins? Ooh! Were Harry's dark powers going to manifest to protect you, proving his undying love for you?"

"I thought... I..."

"Oh just spit it out. I already know it had to be stupid, or romantic, or both! Its not like anything you say could be more embarrassing than what the rumor mill is going to come up with."

"Where do you even come up with that stuff!"

"I'd risk getting beat up by several dozen students for that! To channel my dark lord's powers again... But seriously, why were you there?"

"I thought I should apologize to Draco."

"You... you... you..."

Hermione watched in dawning horror as Tracey's eyes went from confusion to a moment of eureka and her mouth spread in a wide maniacal smile.

"You tried to kill Draco because you're secretly in love with him but couldn't have him because you're a muggleborn and Draco is a pureblood, but now... ah... now its been discovered that you really had wizard parents and maybe he'll forgive all and recognize the advantages in making you the next Lady Malfoy!"

"What? But that doesn't even..."

"No, wait. You're soul-bound to Harry, of course – can you be soul-bound against your will? – but Harry traded you to the Malfoys to save your life! And since you were in love with Draco anyway, ever since he caught you on the roof..."

"Harry and I are not soul-bound, whatever that even means! I don't even think that's a real thing!"

"But otherwise?"

"What? No!"

"If you and Harry aren't seeing each other anymore, can I have him? You don't have to take Draco. I mean, I was plotting to marry both of them..."

"ggihakjgh."

Tracey grabbed her wrists with an eager expression on her face. "Please tell me that was yes in Swahili or Goblin or some other language."

Hermione sat down abruptly, pulling Tracey down with her. She couldn't think, overwhelmed.

Tracey crouched in front of her, dropping her wrists and putting her hands on her shoulders. "Hermione, are you okay? You don't have to decide all at once. But if you were also plotting to marry both of them, well, it'll be easier if we agree to divide them up and not waste our efforts fighting over them." The Slytherin witch let go of her shoulders and rocked back on her heels. "Unless you want to come to one of those... you know... arrangements. Does that work with four people?"

Hermione was deliberately trying to tune Tracey out, in part to stop the onslaught of insanity, and in part because a voice she identified as Harry was reminding her that it was better to neither confirm nor deny wild speculation. That seemed like remarkably good advice, given she couldn't actually tell Tracey what happened.

"Tracey! You know I can't talk about what happened, so I can neither confirm nor deny that... uhh... Harry traded me to the Malfoys so they'd spare my life." That was remarkably hard to say. How did Harry say stuff like that with a straight face? "And how likely do you think you'll randomly guess the right thing by wildly speculating?"

"So... you aren't relinquishing your claim on Harry?" Tracey's face fell a little. "What about one of those... you know..."

"Gaaaaak."

"Well, think about it?"

"Oh Merlin I hope not!" A voice in her head followed up with, see, you can curse!

Tracey pulled herself into a sitting position next to Hermione, hands on her knees in front of her. "You know, as long as we're talking, I could use some help with something..."

"So long as it doesn't have anything to do with Harry... or Draco... or one of... ick."

"No, not at all. Well, I'm pretty sure not... No, Daphne seems way too normal for that... or is it the normal ones you have to watch out for..." Tracey stared off into space in thought.

"Wait, what about Daphne?"

"Oh, she's so sad now after her mother... you know... the 'dementor disaster'".

It had been awful just sitting there watching when she hadn't known any of the victims, but some of them would have children. Children her age. Greengrass was a Most Ancient and Noble House, of course her mother was there. Her mother who had just happened to vote to send Hermione to Azkaban. Hermione felt sick.

"So, I was thinking, I should figure out a way to cheer her up... You don't look so good."

"I... I... I can't talk about it." Hermione was near tears.

"S-Sorry I brought it up. I forgot, you were actually there. Was it awful?" The other girl's eyes were wide.

"Awful..." Hermione muttered. Tracey had no idea.

"Well, at least you had Harry to protect you. But Daphne isn't eating or going to classes or anything, so I thought I should do something."

Hermione shook her head. Protect her? No. Remembering the events that ended the Wizengamot session was not productive. "How could we help cheer up Daphne?"

"She's really sad, so I thought it would have to be something really special. And when I'm upset or sad, thinking about boys makes me happy. Or plotting. Or plotting that involves getting boys." Tracey put her hands behind her and leaned back on her arms. "And I'd think actually having a boy there would be even better. And its not like we can make her plot, but we might be able to convince a boy..."

Hermione's face turned red. "What exactly are you thinking about?"

"Well, when I'm thinking about boys, it's usually Harry, and I channel his dread powers, and then he..." Tracey gestured with her near hand.

"No, really, I don't need... Forget I asked."

"Sorry, I know Harry is yours, and it's not always Harry. Sometimes it's Draco. Or..."

"Tracey!"

"What, it's not like I've imagined you and he and myself having one of those..."

"...please stop..."

"... maybe I should. What do people do with three people anyway?" Tracey's near hand went to her chin. "I mean, it would be kind of hard to kiss two people at the same time, wouldn't it? And where do they put all the hands?"

"Would you at least have the courtesy to blush when you say stuff like that?" Hermione almost yelled. Finding someone to Obliviate this entire conversation was starting to look particularly appealing. She didn't want to be thinking about this. Good girls did not think about this.

"You should hear the stuff I overhear some of the older Slytherin girls saying in the bathroom. I'm not even sure its all anatomically possible."

Hermione's right hand came up, index finger crooked, as if uncertain what it should point at. She started to open her mouth and then shut it. Her brain wouldn't even form the question.

"And then there's the group of older girls who write stories about other students... and professors... and other... things... I mean, Hogwarts/Giant Squid, who comes up with this stuff?"

Hermione put her head in her hands. "Why me?" she asked softly.

"So anyway, all we have to do is figure out a nice boy whom Daphne likes. Then we need to manipulate that boy into going to Daphne, but that shouldn't be hard. I mean, she's noble and pretty. Any boy should want to be her boyfriend, right? There's just some boy code about appearing weak in front of other boys."

"Your plan is to find a nice boy..." At least this seemed like a safer conversation thread than... whatever it was Tracey liked to think about.

"...that Daphne likes!"

"...and get him to give her a shoulder to cry on?"

"Well, and hopefully kiss..."

"...and this will make Daphne happy?" Did Harry make her happy? Sometimes. But also angry. And frequently confused. Boys didn't seem like the answer to everything. And the kissing thing... that hadn't worked out so well.

"...unless what she actually wants is a wizard who will use her to channel his dark powers? But there's already you and me – how many other girls could there be in our class who want that?"

Hermione's mouth opened, but she was again speechless.

"What do you and Harry go off and do by yourselves anyway?"

She shook her head to clear it. "What? Read. Or talk. Or science. Why?" She mentally kicked herself immediately after speaking. She was starting to see the value in Harry's policy of denying everything.

"Science?"

"We... experiment?"

"Ooh, I think I've heard some of the older Slytherin girls talking about 'experimenting'. Do tell!" The Slytherin girl rotated her torso to face her, leaning in conspiratorially.

"With magic," she said quickly, thinking that would explain everything.

"Well duh, where do you think they get the tentacles from?" Tracey asked, her arms thrown wide.

"What? ... buh... … Ack!" Hermione fell backwards, suddenly glad she was sitting on the floor. Still the floor was awful hard when she cracked her head on it. "Ow."

Tracey leaned over her. "Are you okay? Was it something I said?"

"Is there anything else you'd like to mention about Mister Potter?"

McGonagall arched her eyebrows at the flame in the fireplace of the Headmaster's Office. "I'm quite sure that's enough to cause plenty of trouble."

"Shall we review and make sure nothing has been left off? Original discovery in transmutation. Realized the fundamental principle of potionry." The sound of a pen making a mark after each item carried through the flames as Amelia Bones read off the list she had made. "Owns an invisibility cloak."

"You'd have to ask Albus for more information about that."

"... if I can find him. A new charm which 'blinds dementors' … and apparently destroys them if my eyes are to be believed."

"Albus did not care to share that particular effect of the charm with me, if he even knew."

"Muggle-raised with a keen interest in muggle artifacts. Has a time turner. Is an occlumens."

"Also Albus's doing."

"And apparently deduced or discovered a secret which lets him command dementors."

Minerva remembered that moment quite clearly. The all-too-calm young boy's voice cast before the storm of the dementor's fury. Dementors are death. She must have visibly reacted, because she lost track of whatever Director Bones was saying until disturbed from her revery by a polite cough from the other side of the flames.

"You look pale as a ghost."

"I would hope what happened would be enough to shake even the strongest of us."

Amelia's eyes cast downward, possibly reading over the list one more time, before looking back at her. "Are you certain Mr. Potter was not involved in freeing Bellatrix Black from Azkaban?"

"His time turner is restricted to evening use, and he managed a full 6 hour shift that night. If he were involved, his time turner was not... and the defense professor would be implicated as well." Now that was a frightening thought.

"They are close?"

"I could not say how close, but Harry did make several weekend trips to Diagon Alley with Professor Quirrel."

"Mister Potter isn't secretly an animagus, is he?"

"Not that I'm aware, and what I know of his activities wouldn't have left much time for the meditation. Nor would I expect Mister Potter to become one without proper instruction, supervision, and registration – but then I hadn't expected what happened at the trial either."

"No matter, we have ways of testing such things."

"If that is all, Amelia, I really do have a lot of things to do today."

"You've been most helpful, Minerva. I hope we can have a more productive working relationship than Dumbledore and I did."

"As do I. Oh, Amelia, would you be so kind as to return our defense professor to us soon? NEWTs are coming up, after all."

"We are concluding our investigation of his actions with respect to Lord Malfoy's heir. Barring some unforeseen complication, I expect he'll be released shortly. I may need to borrow him again in the matter of Bellatrix's escape."

"If at all possible, please wait until after NEWTs. Good day, Amelia."

In the end it was decided, mostly by Tracey, that they needed additional help finding a suitable boy. We clearly don't have normal tastes in boys – we should find someone who does! Which of course meant they had to decide who would have normal taste in boys.

That wasn't totally accurate, actually. Tracey had floated the idea of seeing if Daphne had a journal and using it to find someone she liked. But, in addition to the obvious difficulty of any such journal being near Daphne's bed, which was perpetually occupied by her at the moment – a difficulty that didn't seem to bother Tracey at all – Tracey also insisted that Daphne might be attracted to 'bad boys' who wouldn't be any good for her – apparently that's what most women really wanted, according to Slytherin upperclasswomen gossip – and what Daphne actually needed was a boy who would be good for her. Hermione had just acquiesced at that point. Even trying to think through what passed for Tracey logic had required too many parentheticals to express to actually make sense. Not that her brain hadn't dutifully complied and made the necessary mental circumlocutions, but she wasn't thinking about it. Really.

Which meant now they needed to decide whom to ask. Yes, this was completely sensible and not even a little silly. Not at all. Hermione was most definitely not questioning why any other girl would do better than they were – not that they had really come up with anything, mind you – but just about every other girl Hermione had heard give relationship advice had been crazy. Clearly there was something about boys which just caused girls' brains to switch off. Regardless, given the advice she'd received in the past, trying to find a boy who might actually bring happiness, immediate happiness, to Daphne was a lost cause. 'You just don't understand male psychology. Granger's got to make it look like she can mysteriously resist his seductive charm.' Madness.

"Maybe we should ask Lavender?" Tracey asked. Former SPHEW associates seemed to be the obvious choice.

"Lavender with her hero outfit?"

"Sure, why not?"

"Well, we aren't exactly looking for a hero, and I'm pretty sure that's who she's looking for."

"The brave knight come to rescue Daphne from her depression! 'Here milady, have a shoulder to cry on.'" Tracey threw her voice as low as she could. Hermione couldn't help a small laugh.

"Well, the Slytherin dorms are in a dungeon. A perfect location for a rescue." Hermione observed with a smile. If you were going to do something crazy, might as well get in the spirit of the occasion.

"'My hero!'" Tracey threw her voice higher than usual, and put the back of her hand on her forehead in a mock swoon.

"Really not sure we're going to get any good ideas from Lavender, though."

"We don't have to tell her why we're asking. Just ask about which boys she thinks are nice, and then we can decide whether any of them are worthy of 'our lady' Daphne."

Entertaining failure would at least be entertaining, which was better than what most of her life had been like recently. No time like the present.

Tracey was indefatigable, and they'd gone through much of the Gryffindor common room while they'd been there. Talking about boys was exhausting. And they'd heard so many recommendations that, afterwards, they'd decided they had too much information. And they weren't sure which Gryffindors could be trusted to give good advice on boys.

At least hanging out with Gryffindors hadn't been uncomfortable, well, not in the way that Ravenclaw was currently uncomfortable. Rather than her pariah status in her own house, Hermione felt like she was a celebrity in Gryffindor. Admittedly it made her feel uncomfortable in a different way, but she wasn't thinking about that right now. At all.

"I'll give you this much," Hermione said, as they left the vicinity of the Gryffindor first year dorms, "this is a better plan than your idea to tie Harry up and cart him around to find bullies. At least we'll ultimately choose someone, right?"

"Hey, that would have worked! We should have tried! You'll come to appreciate my strategic brilliance once I prove I'm not the one who's crazy!" The maniacal laughter that followed was not convincing.

Hermione supposed it was inevitable that they'd end up going to Hannah. Hannah was kind and shy and, according to Tracey, almost certain to only like clean-cut 'good boys'. 'Unless of course she's hiding a bad girl streak, but I don't think she has it in her.' Hermione was doubly glad she didn't listen to... whatever it was older Slytherin girls talked about.

Hermione really should have seen this coming.

They'd gotten Hannah out into the hallway, along with Susan Bones who was justifiably curious, because the Hufflepuff common room was simply too uncomfortable for Hermione. Tracey had already asked the question, 'are there any boys you think are nice?', when Hermione remembered the conversation SPHEW had immediately after the protest. 'There's a boy I like.' No, that wasn't the specifically relevant memory, it was Daphne speaking. 'She likes Neville Longbottom, actually.' But what made Hermione uncomfortable was not the knowledge that Neville was almost certainly the boy Hannah was going to name. 'And unfortunately for her, he's going to marry someone else. It's very tragic.' It was obvious, once you thought about it, not that Hermione had been very interested in the topic at the time. She knew who Daphne liked.

"Um, you promise not to tell?"

"Tracey..." Hermione started.

Tracey gave her a look. "Of course we won't tell. We're your friends, right?"

"Well, I think Neville is nice," Hannah said softly.

"Tracey, maybe we should rethink this?"

"No no, Neville's perfect. I mean, he was number four on my list, but I'd give him up for Daphne."

"Um?" Hannah squeaked.

"Wait, what?" said Susan, injecting herself in the conversation. "What exactly are you plotting? What does Daphne have to do with this?"

"I'm going to cheer Daphne up by giving her Neville Longbottom!" Tracey smiled hugely.

"But..." Hannah looked at Hermione with large eyes.

"Tracey, maybe we should reconsider..."

"Oh no, I have the perfect plan." There was a gleam in Tracey's eyes as she rubbed her hands together.

The three other girls looked at each other with various expressions. Hannah's look was closest to horror, Hermione merely uncomfortable, Susan confused but disapproving.

"Tracey, you don't just give people to other people," Susan said sternly.

"I thought we were going to convince whomever to..." Hermione was stopped by an evil laugh from Tracey. That was not a good sign. Wait. "No Tracey! You are not stunning Neville, tying him up, and dragging him down to the Slytherin dungeons!"

"Aw, but that would work for sure this time."

"That's not the solution to everything!"

"You mean there are problems that can't be solved by stunning a boy and tying him up?"